<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>CH's Blog</title><link>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on CH's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 22:41:01 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Booking Hotels - Quick Tip for Extra 15%-20% Off</title><link>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/sg-money-hacks/cheaper-hotels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 22:41:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/sg-money-hacks/cheaper-hotels/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go on at least one trip every year, and one of the biggest expenses is always the accommodation. Imagine you spend $200 dollars per night for 10 days — $2000 in total. Imagine again you know the trick to save 15% to 20% on each booking — that is $300 to $400 dollars saved! In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you exactly how to find such deals, and it&amp;rsquo;s simpler than you think.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Keychron Singapore - Quick Tip for 15% Off</title><link>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/sg-money-hacks/keychron-singapore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 18:29:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/sg-money-hacks/keychron-singapore/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2025 Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Keychron has &lt;a href="https://www.keychronsg.com/"&gt;officially arrived in Singapore&lt;/a&gt;, so the price difference may not be as much anymore, but getting directly from the US site can still be a better deal!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR You can buy Keychron directly from their US official website and ship to Singapore without any extra tax!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keychron keyboards sold by dealers in Singapore are usually more expensive than the price on Keychron&amp;rsquo;s official website, not to mention Keychron often has sales that makes the price difference even more stark.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to Create a Logseq Plugin</title><link>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/tech/logseq-plugin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:41:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/tech/logseq-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I discovered &lt;a href="https://logseq.com/"&gt;Logseq&lt;/a&gt;, I have been using it as my daily note taking tool. It has a lot of powerful features, and if you think something is missing, you could easily find or write a plugin that suits your needs. In this post, I will show you how to write your own Logseq plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be implementing a command that we could use in the Logseq editor. In particular, the command will fetch the current market price data of a stock from the internet and display it in the editor:
&lt;img alt="Demo GIF" loading="lazy" src="https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/tech/logseq-plugin/images/demo.gif"&gt;
Fun fact: I personally wrote and used this simple plugin to speed up my stock analysis workflow using Logseq📈.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deposit and Withdraw USD on Webull Singapore With 0 Fee</title><link>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/investing/deposit-withdraw-webull-sg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 10:48:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/investing/deposit-withdraw-webull-sg/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I opened a Webull Singapore account and the experience has been good so far. However, although the fee structure for deposits and withdrawals in SGD (with a Singapore bank account) is clearly stated, it&amp;rsquo;s not so clear on depositing/withdrawing other currencies like USD using a multi-currency account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Webull uses a DBS multi-currency account under the hood to hold our funds, supposedly if we deposit or withdraw USD using a DBS multi-currency account as well, there should be no charges. Sadly, there&amp;rsquo;s no official statement to verify the assumption, not to mention the scary &amp;ldquo;SGD20 charged by remitting bank for USD&amp;rdquo; mentioned on the &lt;a href="https://www.webull.com.sg/help/faq/1062-Are-there-any-withdrawal-fees"&gt;official FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Migrate From create-react-app to Next.js for Static Site Generation</title><link>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/tech/react-to-nextjs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 21:12:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/tech/react-to-nextjs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was building my &lt;a href="https://cookiehoodie.github.io"&gt;portfolio site&lt;/a&gt; using React and the built-in create-react-app toolchain. The webpage worked well and I was able to deploy it on GitHub Pages with ease. However, create-react-app uses client-side rendering, which causes an obvious layout shift of the components when the page is first loaded or refreshed. Not a big deal, but it&amp;rsquo;s annoying😠.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the webpage doesn&amp;rsquo;t change often, the best solution is to utilize static site generation (SSG), which pre-renders the page and thus eliminate the layout shift. Unfortunately, create-react-app doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide the functionality out of the box, and although there are some third-party packages such as react-snap that do the job, they are outdated and don&amp;rsquo;t support the latest React versions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using Docker with VSCode for Local Development</title><link>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/tech/docker-vscode-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 10:45:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cookiehoodie.github.io/blog/posts/tech/docker-vscode-development/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever we want to start working on a new project with new tools or frameworks, the first step is always to install the dependencies for local development. However, the installation process could be painful especially if different versions of existing tools are needed, forcing us to have multiple versions that eat up the storage space on our device. Not to mention, the installed tools could be located all over the place, making it hard to locate and uninstall them when they are no longer needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>